a group of researchers decided to grow
the tiny human brains that we can grow
from stem cells in an egg and it is
possibly the best paper I have read in a
very long time in case you are not
familiar one of the biggest problems
that scientists have growing the tiny
human brains is that they don't last
that long they almost always expire a
hypoxia and vascularizing them has been
challenging now chickens do not have a
placenta so they end up vascularizing
with the tissues of an egg in order to
exchange oxygen with the outside world I
see where they got this idea and it is
honestly brilliant as you go through
this paper it is very obvious that the
people in this lab work with chickens so
they took a fertilized egg and they cut
a little hole on top they would then
just pop a slightly mature brain
organoid right in there it amazes me
that it doesn't matter if it's a chicken
or a human brain it'll just vascularize
but I don't work with chickens now this
is a j paper J if you're not familiar
with that is a website where we
essentially let methods go to die it's
essentially a method that was no longer
useful but you spent so much time and
effort on it you just wanted people to
see it turns out you can incubate a
brain organoid at the same temperature
that you incubate a chicken some of the
directions on here are just hilarious to
me like don't forget to put a bigger
bandage on now some of their results
were surprising like their younger brain
organoids so the ones that were
transferred earlier on in the process of
development survived better than the
older ones which is contrary to what
people have seen with grafting them onto
brains usually usually the more
developed ones do a little bit better
and then what is possibly the best line
I've ever read in any paper even though
egg rotation seems mandatory for the
proper development of the chicken
embryos during incubation it is
necessary to avoid it after puncturing
the air chamber okay so you don't really
need a healthy chicken if you're just
growing a brain organoid that shouldn't
even be a concern it'll still develop
but I appreciate that they included that
in there if one is somebody who works
with chickens I imagine that's a big
concern so what they actually found is
that yes the brain organoids would
vascularize with the chickens it
probably also does have quite a bit of
chicken cells now contaminating it Jo
papers usually don't go into much detail
it's just representative results this is
what we did I am going to send them an
email because there's some things I want
to know too like how much human brain
tissue ended up in the chicken if any at
all now the reason it probably ended up
on J is because there are now better
methods to vascularize a brain organ oid
including what seems to be the best
method which is just pop it in the head
of something else human brain organoids
have been popped into the skulls of maak
monkeys and mice and rats they did say
that they chose these methods because
rejection was unlikely and I'm not
entirely sure what rejection looks like
in a chicken but imuno insufficient
animals are usually used when these
kinds of grafts are done that is done
out of an abundance of caution the brain
is not a likely place to have rejection
anyway but we are talking about popping
an entirely different organ organism
together I do also want to reiterate
even though it ended up on Jo it is
still a really brilliant idea I'm I
impressed are
youo compx than the tiny proar swarming
in the culture